A Guide to the 8th Evacuation Hospital 1941-2011
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- Letter from McLemore Birdsong to Fellows and group photo of the Department of Pediatrics and former residents 1960 November 11, Photo 1-B&W 8 x 10 mounted, 1 TDS 1 pg., 1 sticker (Box-folder 22-071)
  The letter was written on the occasion of the presentation of the Wendal Waddell portrait to UVa School of Medicine. Left to right, bottom row: Jack Humphries, Bob Hightower, Reed Hopkins, THE CHIEF, Bill Wray, Mac Birdsong, Betty Whitehead, Willie Grossman; second row: Nat Ewell, Charlie Gleason, Harry Austin, Bill Harman, Page Booker, Jim Stone, Warren Gregory, Andy Townes, Joe Mitchell; top row: Dan Anderson, Jimmy Etheridge, Jimmy Wood, Julia Edmunds, Morris Lambdin, Fred Mitchell, Bill Thomnpson, Bill Liddle, Cam L'Engle, Gene Frame, Wiltsie Young, Fletcher Harrell
- Note from Lallah M. E[dwards] Anderson accompanying New Testament and flag ND, Artifact: New Testament, 1 silk USA flag 7.5 x 12 inches, 1 ANS 1 pg. 1 (Box-folder 22-072)
  The note indicates the New Testament was given on Feb. 8, 1943 and carried and used throughout WW II. The flag was given to Anderson by Myrtle Hall from UVa who used it throughout WW I.
- Group photo of 8th Evac reunion at Boar's Head Inn, Charlottesville, VA 1985, Photo 1-color 8 x 10 (Box-folder 23-001)
- Pins: one in the shape of "M," the other "C" ND, Artifact: 2 silver-colored metal pins (Box-folder 23-002)
  donated by Cathleene Carter
- Ruptured Duck honorable discharge patches - World War II ND, Artifact: 3 green cloth patches with yellow embroidery (Box-folder 23-003)
- Cathleene Carter in Ischia, Italy ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-004)
- Group photo of 8th Evac reunion at Alumni Hall, UVa, Charlottesville, VA 1960 August, Photo 1-B&W 5.5 x 14 (Box-folder 23-005)
- Names and addresses of 1970 8th Evac reunion attendees and non attendees 1970 August, 1 TD 4 pp. (Box-folder 23-006)
- List of 8th Evac members deceased prior to 1970 and from 1970-1975 1975, 1TD with AN (Box-folder 23-007)
- Letter from the Charlottesville Group to the Eighth Evacer regarding 1960 reunion 1960 November 7, 1 TL, 2 TD, 9 pp. (Box-folder 23-008)
  Enclosed are the names and addresses of all who attended as well as those that did not attend the 1960 reunion
- Pink ribbon tied in a bow ND, ribbon (Box-folder 23-009)
- Structure, Carinola 1944, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-010)
- Building with ornate door, Carinola 1944, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-011)
- Five military personnel, 3 women, 2 men at Vesuvius 1944, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-012)
- Woman looking out of tent in Algiers ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.25 x 5 (Box-folder 23-013)
- Cathleene Carter with unidentified man ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-014)
- Pietramala, the day Billie left ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-015)
  Left to right: Betsy, Billie, Cathleene Carter, Madge, and Northrup
- Left to right: Kate Robinson and Cathleene Carter in front of 8th Evac Hospital sign ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-016)
- Ship with military personnel on board ND, Photo 1-B&W 3 x 4.25 (Box-folder 23-017)
  Notation on back: What we came home on
- Ruins, church at Carinola, Italy ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-018)
- tents, truck, military personnel ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.75 x 4.75 (Box-folder 23-019)
- George Hairfield, Ruth Eastman, and Rich Low in front of tents at Carinola, Italy 1944, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-020)
- Cathleene Carter standing on a balcony 1945, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 4.25 (Box-folder 23-021)
  Notation on back includes: Streasa [Stresa?]
- Cathleene Carter holding a bucket outside a tent in Italy 1945, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-022)
- Clothed Cathleene Carter sitting in latrine ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-023)
- Latrine showing cans holding toilet paper rolls ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-024)
- Cathleene Carter standing by tent ND, Photo 1-B&W 3 x 4.75 (Box-folder 23-025)
- Unidentified woman by ladder ND, Photo 1-B&W 3 x 4.75 (Box-folder 23-026)
- Cathleene Carter standing on wooden walkway ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-027)
- Unidentified woman and Cathleene Carter on right of photo ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-028)
- Cathleene Carter standing outside holding a walking stick ND, Photos 2-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-029)
- Cathleene Carter in Capri ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-030)
- Cathleene Carter next to wooden building ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-031)
  Notation on back: [Camp] Kilmer
- Cathleene Carter next to wooden building ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-032)
  Same building as 23-031 identified as [Camp] Kilmer; Notation on back: Ex 451 C-6 Annex
- Cathleene Carter, Em[ma Garland?] and Billie at Carinola, Italy 1944, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-033)
- Hubert Holsinger, Cathleene Carter and Dick Morris at Carinola, Italy 1944, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-034)
- Unidentified man and Cathleene Carter in swim suits ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-035)
- Two unidentified men and Cathleene Carter in swimsuits ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-036)
- Cathleene Carter standing in a field ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-037)
- Cathleene Carter standing by a pillar ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-038)
- Cathleene Carter in Capri ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-039)
- Cathleene Carter standing in a field near Pietramala, Italy ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 23-040)
- Cathleene Carter and the Leaning Tower of Pisa ND, Photo 1-B&W 3 x 4.75 (Box-folder 23-041)
- Cathleene Carter standing outside a building on a wooden walkway ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.75 (Box-folder 23-042)
- In front of the Joyce Kilmer Memorial, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-043)
- Fire Department, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-044)
- The Chapel, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-045)
- Receiving mail at Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-046)
- Post Headquarters, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-047)
- A Salute to You from Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-048)
- One of the Theatre buildings, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-049)
- New arrivals, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-050)
- Detail assembling for drill, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-051)
- A Section of the hospital area, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-052)
- One of the many post exchanges, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-053)
- In line for chow, Camp Kilmer, N.J. ND, Postcard (Box-folder 23-054)
- Wrapper for 12 assorted Souvenir Cards, Camp Kilmer, N.J. 10 cents ND, Postcard wrapper with AN (Box-folder 23-055)
- Halloran General Hospital postcard sets ND, 30 Postcards (3 sets, 10 postcards each (Box-folder 23-056)
  Photos taken by U.S. Signal Corps, includes mess hall, reception room, auditorium, kitchen, bakery equipment, x-ray unit, ward scene, nurses' quarters, and acute medical and surgical building
- Army Nurses Branch insignia ND, Artifact: 2 gold-colored metal pins (Box-folder 23-057)
  Cadesus pin with eagle and the letter "N," clutch back post attachment, donated by Cathleene Carter
- Rank Badge - 2nd lieutenant ND, Artifact: 2 gold-colored metal bars (Box-folder 23-058)
- Ruptured Duck honorable discharge pin, World War II 1942-45, Artifact: gold-colored metal pin (Box-folder 23-059)
- European - African - Middle Eastern campaign medal 1942-45, Artifact: metal and cloth pin (Box-folder 23-060)
- Fifth Army pin ND, Artifact: silver=colored metal and red and blue enamel pin (Box-folder 23-061)
- American National Red Cross Nurses pin ND, Artifact: gold-colored metal and red, white and blue enamel (Box-folder 23-062)
  48554 on back of pin, donated by Cathleene Carter
- Rank badge - 1st lieutenant ND, Artifact: 6 silver-colored metal bars (Box-folder 23-063)
- American Legion pin ND, Artifact: gold-plated metal and blue enamel pin (Box-folder 23-064)
- Empty, formerly Dictabelts, now in Boxes 17 and 18 ND, empty (Box-folder 24-000)
- Scrapbooks ND, Artifacts: 2 scrapbooks with many B&W photos (Box-folder 25-000)
  Many photographs are of buildings and the ruins of buildings, interiors, towns, the countryside, and non-military people, including children. There are photos of the 8th Evac, but they do not predominate.
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service June 11, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-001)
  Smokers articles, candy, toilet articles, stationery, miscellaneous items, and nurses articles could be ordered from the PX Warehouse
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 January 10, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-002)
  Smokers articles, candy, toilet articles, stationery, miscellaneous items, nurses articles, and additional items could be ordered from the PX Warehouse
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 January 27, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-003)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 January 27, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-004)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 February 10, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-005)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 March 11, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-006)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 April 5, 1 TD with ANS 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-007)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 April 19, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-008)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 May 6, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-009)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 May 20, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-010)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 June 29, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-011)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 July 27, 1 TD with ANS 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-012)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 August 2, 1 TD with ANS 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-013)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 August 11, 1 TD with ANS 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-014)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 August, 1 TD with ANS 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-015)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 August 26, 1 TD with ANS 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-016)
- Requisition and sales slip, Army Exchange Service 1944 September 27, 1 TD with AN 2 pp. (Box-folder 26-017)
- Yank, the Army Weekly, European edition, Vol. 1, No. 40 1945 January 5, Magazine 24 pp. (Box-folder 26-018)
- The 8th Evac: A History of the University of Virginia Hospital Unit in World War II by Byrd Stuart Leavell bookjackets 1970, paper bookjackets 21 pp. (Box-folder 26-019)
- School of Medicine, Fourth year Class, 1942-43 1942-43, Photo 1-B&W 10.75 x 13.5, 1TD (Box-folder 26-020)
  Medical Class of 1943, left to right, First row: John Dean Adams, Margaret Alford Barnes, Walter Prothro Barnes, Jr., Monte Leroy Binder, Oliver Beirne Bobbitt, Jr., Armistead Page Booker, Richard Booth, Jr., Eugene Calloway, Jr., Joshua Fry Bullitt Camblos, Donal Paul Chance, Sidney William Cohen, James Thomas Colley Second row: William Cassius Cook, Jr., Lewis Franklin Cosby, Jr., Thomas Stilwell Edwards, George Bleecker Ely, Thomas Carter Fowlkes, Irvin Galin, Giles Quarles Gilmer, Milton Sidney Goldman, William Dandridge Haden, Jr., William Gletcher Harrell, Jr., Edward Roberts Hawkins, Charles Herbert Henderson, Jr. Third row: Charles Albert Hudson, Carl William Irwin, Eugene Rhodes Johnston, George Barnard Kegley, Eusebius Milton Kellam, Joseph Kessler, Camillus Saunders L'Engle, Jr., Carl Jay Levine, Myrtle Evelyn Logan, Frank Armstrong McCue, Donald David Markowitz, Samuel Percy Marshall Fourth row: John William Henry Morgan, Raney Archer Oven, John Brewer Petter, Carol LeVan Plott, James Guy Price, George Nicholas Psimas, Charles Frederick Schneider, Nelson Montgomery Smith, Joshua Price Sutherland, Robert McKinney Tankesley, John Covington Tinsley, Jr. Fifth row: Mary Martin Wade, Donald Walters, Walter Motley White, Jr., Harold Stanley Yood, Eugene James Yorkoff
- Nurses and officers on ski holiday at Pietramala, Italy; left to right: Waddell, Bell, Huffman, Casscells, Franklin ND, Photo 1-B&W 11 x 14 (Box-folder 26-021)
- Certificate for Thelma Matthews 1933 November 23, 1 10 x 11.5 certificate (Box-folder 26-022)
  Certificate from the Nurses Examining Board for the State of Virginia states that Matthews is entitled to show she is a registered nurse.
- Certificate for Thelma Matthews 1933 March 19, 1 12 x 15 certificate (Box-folder 26-023)
  Certificate certifies that Matthews has completed three years course of instruction at the University of Virginia Hospital School of Nursing.
- Scrapbook ND, Artifact: scrapbook with many B&W photos (Box-folder 26-024)
  Many photographs are of buildings, interiors, towns, the countryside, and non-military people. Many, if not all, appear to have been taken in North Africa. There are photos of the 8th Evac, but they do not predominate.
- Scrapbook ND, Artifact: scrapbook with many B&W photos (Box-folder 26-025)
  Many photographs are of buildings, interiors, towns, the countryside, a parade, and non-military people, including children. All seem to have been taken in North Africa. There are photos of the 8th Evac, but they do not predominate.
- Certificate of Appreciation from the War Department, Office of the Surgeon General ND, 1 certificate signed (Box-folder 26-026)
  The certificate was presented to the University of Virginia for its sponsorship, organization, and staffing of the 8th Evacuation Hospital.
- Ruth Beery ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-001)
- Moving day - men and boxes outside tents ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-002)
- Moving day - men and boxes; Anfa Hotel in background, Casablanca, Morroco 1943, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-003)
- Soldier receiving an honor in front of assembled troops ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-004)
- Four military police at attention with flags in front of a row of vehicles ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-005)
- Left to right: Scarborough, Hairfield, Thornton, and Holsinger on bikes at the beach ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-006)
- Inside the mess tent ND, Photo 1-B&W 4.25 x 5.25 (Box-folder 27-007)
- Unidentified woman standing by 8th Evac Hospital sign ND, Photo 1-B&W 4.25 x 6 (Box-folder 27-008)
- Ned Waddell' and laughing men around his tent that collapsed while he was asleep at Goat Hill, Algeria 1943 September, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-009)
  Notation on back: I recognize Ted Laird, Norm Thornton, Jim Culbertson, Prentice Kinser, John Haley (hat) Capt. Windham, Lt. Snavely
- Audience of nurses and soldiers seated outside ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-010)
- William Snavely getting Irving Berlin's signature with John Guerrant in background with cup ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-011)
- Moving day: men, equipment and boxes outside ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-012)
- Soldiers standing and sitting on the ground listening to music with tents in background ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-013)
- Wedding of Frances Wells and Frederick Broadfoot in Florence 1945 February 23, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 27-014)
  William Laird is on the far left, Staige Blackford 3rd from left
- Hilda Franklin and Richard Bell cutting their wedding cake 1945 May 26, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 27-015)
- Soldiers and nurses by vehicles getting ready to go to Ischia, Italy ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-016)
  Notation on back includes: Two of them got married! Frankie and Dick, Lt. Monin, Don Watson? Peterson?, Orsini?
- Tents, jeeps and road ND, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 27-017)
- Soldiers standing around a litter ND, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 27-018)
- Soldier cleaning boots ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 27-019)
- Tents with water in background ND, Photo 1-B&W 5 x 7 (Box-folder 27-020)
- Pharmacy ND, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 27-021)
- The pharmacy at the 8th Evac 1945 January 13, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 27-022)
  Hilton Nau behind the counter dispenses goods to Joseph Dziuba. Harry Wright is in the background. Armed Forces Institute of Pathology photo 5/MM-45-762
- Stone street and building with 8th Evac sign ND, Photo 1-B&W 4.5 x 5.75 (Box-folder 27-023)
- Soldier standing in snow by barrel with spigot ND, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 27-024)
- Soldier standing in mud ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 27-025)
- Men at work in the Registrar's and Evacuation Office at the 8th Evac 1945 January 13, Photo 1-B&W 4 x 5 (Box-folder 27-026)
  Armed Forces Institute of Pathology photo 5/MM-45-769
- Letter from Tony Sampas to Joan Echtenkamp Kline concerning his uncle Sebastian Sampas ND, 1 envelope, 1 TLS, 2 TD, 26 pp. (Box-folder 27-027)
  The enclosed papers about Sebastian who died in World War II include his poetry.
- 1943 Diary of William Laird 1943-44, diary 98 pp. (Box-folder 27-028)
  includes dates of religious services, movement and location of 8th Evac, books read by Laird, addresses, and discretionary fund account; donated by his daughter, Marion Laird Gould
- "House Organ:" "Memories of the 'Good War'" 1990 May, 1 magazine extract with AN, 4 pp., 1 magazine with AN, 16 pp. (Box-folder 27-029)
  The article is about Alice Huffman Bugel
- Letter from Virginia C. Macey to Janet Pearson 2001 April 17, 1 photocopied photo, 1 TLS, 2 photocopied TLS 4 pp. (Box-folder 27-030)
  Macey writes concerning her uncle, Joseph Crouch, who was buried at Pietramala, Italy
- Alice Huffman Bugel standing in mud at Pietramala, Italy ND, Photo 1-B&W 3.25 x 4.5 (Box-folder 27-031)
- Letter from Beverley Tucker to John Guerrant 2000 October 2, 1 ALS, 1TD 6 pp. (Box-folder 27-032)
  enclosed with letter is "Personal Reflections of the 8th Evac. Hospital" by Beverley D. Tucker, Jr.
- Venice - Ponte di Rialto 1943, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-033)
- Venice - Ponte Nuovo della Stazione e Chiesa degli Scalzi 1943, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-034)
- Venice - La Gondola 1943, Postcard 1-color 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-035)
- Lago di Garda - Riva - Strada del Ponale ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-036)
- Venice - Ponte di Rialto ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-037)
- Venice - Palazzo Ducale - Sala del Maggior Consiglio ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-038)
- Venice - Facciata della Chiesa di S. Maria dei Miracoli ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-039)
- Venice - Basilica della Salute ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-040)
- Venice - Rio della maravegie 1943, Postcard 1-color 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-041)
- Venice - Ponte del Sospiri Seufzerbrucke ND, Postcard 1-color 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-042)
- Venice - Panorama del Canal Grande ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-043)
- Venice - Chiesa della Salute ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-044)
- Pompei - Casa dei Vetti ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-045)
- Pompei - Teatro grande ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-046)
- Pompei - I Propilei del Foro Triangolare ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-047)
- Pompei - Terme del foro - tepidarium ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-048)
- Pompei - Casa di Cecilio Giocondo ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-049)
- Pompei - Arco di Nerone ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-050)
- Pompei - Panorama dal Tempio di Grove ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-051)
- Pompei - Strada Consolare ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-052)
- Rome - Roman Forum - Temple of Antonius and Faustina ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 4 x 6 (Box-folder 27-053)
- Tome - Panorama dal Colosseo, con Via dell'Impero ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-054)
- Rome - Mercati Trainesi e Casa dei Cavalieri di Rodi ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-055)
- Lago di Garda, Gardesana Occidentale _ Tra la Roccio ed il Lago ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-056)
- Rome - Via Appia, Tomb of Cecilia Metella ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-057)
- Rome - Monumento a Vittoria Emanuele ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-058)
- Rome - forum Mussolini ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-059)
- Rome - Theater of Marcellus ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-060)
- Rome - Roman Forum ND, Postcard 1-Brown & White 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-061)
- Leaning tower of Pisa ND, Postcard 1-B&W 3.75 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-062)
- Hanging of Benito Mussolini and his mistress, Claretta Petacci, Rome 1945 April 29, Photo card 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-063)
- The hanging of Claretta Petacci, mistress of Benito Mussolini, Rome 1945 April 29, Photo card 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-064)
- The hanging of Benito Mussolini, his mistress Claretta Petacci, and four others, Rome 1945 April 29, Photo card 1-B&W 3.5 x 5.5 (Box-folder 27-065)
- Computer print-out of the web exhibit: The 8th Evacuation Hospital: The University of Virginia in World War II 2000 December, TD 55 pp. (Box-folder 27-066)
  This copy was used to make spiral bound books.
- Personal comments of John Guerrant's experience with the 8th Evac hospital 2000 June 25, TD 2 pp. (Box-folder 27-067)
- The 8th Evacuation Hospital: The University of Virginia in World War II 2001 January, spiral-bound book (Box-folder 27-068)
  This book was printed from the web exhibit for the UVa Medical Alumni Association Annual Advisory Meeting, January 26-28, 2001.
- Letter from John Guerrant to Former Members of the 8th Evacuation Hospital Unit 2000 July 11, 1 TLS 1 pg. (Box-folder 27-069)
  Guerrant writes about the 8th Evac web exhibit and solicits personal recollections from the former members.
- Norman Thornton ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.75 (Box-folder 28-001)
- Kate Robinson shoveling mud out of a tent near Florence ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-002)
- Nurses of the 8th Evac, left to right: Kate Robinson, Lelia Langhorne Cloyd, Hilda Franklin and Alice Huffman [1944], Photo 1-B&W 3.5 x 4.5 (Box-folder 28-003)
- Ruth Eastman sitting in the mountains ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3 (Box-folder 28-004)
- Lelia Langhorne Cloyd ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-005)
- Thelma Matthews in doorway between two unidentified women ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-006)
- John McKoan and Mary McCone ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-007)
- Kate Robinson standing by wooden steps ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-008)
- John McKoan in center with kitchen help ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-009)
- Mary McCone eating ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-010)
- Hilda Franklin in nurses uniform and cap standing at corner of a building ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-011)
- Hilda Franklin by wooden steps and building ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-012)
- Hilda Franklin in nurses uniform, cap, and cape in front of a building and wooden steps ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-013)
- Hilda Franklin in front of a building and wooden steps ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-014)
- Three people in gas masks ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.5 x 3.5 (Box-folder 28-015)
- Tent mates in Italy ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 28-016)
  left to right: Alice Huffman, Ella Gillespie, Thelma Matthews and Kate Robinson
- Nurses standing in a row ND, Photo 1-B&W 2.75 x 4.5 (Box-folder 28-017)
  left to right: Alice Law, Thelma Matthews, Lelia Langhorne Cloyd, Hilda Franklin, Alice Huffman (?), Ella Gillespie, Kate Robinson